March 28th, 1990

+32 (0) 479/196.976 +44 (0) 7309 255956 +1 (424) 644-6284

Profile

Experienced, fast, and motivated Software Engineer specialized in C# (desktop and backend) and C/C++ (3D and Computer Vision).

I attach a lot of importance to the quality and readability of the code I write and like to keep myself up to date with the latest technologies.

During my career, I have developed and designed various types of projects including desktop/mobile applications, web services, 3D and image analysis libraries,...

Experience

- Senior Software Engineer 03/2018-07/2019
 YDT, Shanghai, China
 - Designed and developed desktop applications.
 - Developed multiple RESTful APIs using microservices.
 - Migrated .Net applications to .Net Core.
 - Designed and developed libraries to analyse and process images and 3D data.
- Software Engineer 03/2015-12/2017
 Co-Founder

TC2 Labs, APEX, North Carolina

- Developed multiple RESTful and WebSocket APIs
- Managed, redesigned, and reduced cost of cloud infrastructure.
- Developed and maintained desktop applications.
- Software Developer

03/2012-03/2015

DNA Interactif Fashion, Kortrijk, Belgium

- Designed, developed, and maintained various desktop applications (shopping, 3D visualization).
- Designed and managed cloud infrastructure.
- Developed multiple APIs using REST, TCP sockets, and WCF.
- Developed a 3D rendering engine and physics simulation libraries.
- o Developed an online 3D virtual shop.
- o 3D Modeling.
- Seasonal worker 03/2010-04/2010
 Walibi Belgium, Wavre, Belgium
- IT work experience 02/2008-02/2008 Informatic Services IS, Louvain-La-Neuve, Belgium

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional Developer:
 - Windows Developer 4
- Microsoft Certified Technology Specialist:
 - Windows Applications
 - Data Access
 - Service Communication Applications

Skills

- Programming Languages:
 - o C#, C++/CLI, Visual Basic
 - o C++, C, CMake, assembly
 - o T-SQL
 - Java
- Cloud Environments:
 - Microsoft Azure
- Frameworks:
 - .Net, .Net Core
 - Asp.Net (Core)
 - Entity Framework (Core)
- UI:
 - o WPF, XAML, WinForms
 - MFC
 - Blazor, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Patterns:
 - MVVM, MVC
 - CAB
- 3D / Computer Vision:
 - OpenCV
 - OpenGL
 - PCL
- Source Control:
 - Git
 - Team Foundation Server
- 3D Software:
 - Autodesk Maya
 - Unity

Education

- Developer .Net 4.0 2011-2011
 Techno.bel, Loyers, Belgium
- Medicine / Psychology 2008-2009 Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium
- Computer Technician 2006-2008
 CEPES Jodoigne, Belgium